<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Race Conditions</title>
    <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Race Conditions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 21:26:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://blog.race-conditions.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Kubernetes Deployments</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/working-with-kubernetes-deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 21:26:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/working-with-kubernetes-deployments/</guid>
      <description>When I first started working with Kubernetes Deployments, the defacto way to create a deployment was to write up some configuration into a YAML file and run kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; apply -f &amp;lt;file&amp;gt;. This made it easy to make changes to the deployment later. Simply, make the required changes in the file and run kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; apply -f &amp;lt;filename&amp;gt;. However, recently after following some Google Kubernetes Engine tutorials, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten into a habit of creating deployments using the kubectl --namespace=&amp;lt;somespace&amp;gt; run command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Interviewing for Python Developer Roles</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-on-interviewing-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jun 2018 14:25:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/notes-on-interviewing-python/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, I opened my Twitter DMs for questions about tech interviews for Python developer roles. I received lots of great questions from junior developers looking for their first software engineering role and from more experienced developers looking to make a change to Python development. Because there seems to be sufficient interest in interviewing for Python dev roles, I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to compile the notes that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken over my four years of interviewing for Python developer roles and publish them here for the benefit of anyone applying or thinking of applying for a Python developer job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Engineer Contracting in the UK</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/software-engineer-contracting-in-the-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 13:46:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/software-engineer-contracting-in-the-uk/</guid>
      <description>Last summer, I handed in my resignation at BigCorp. Although there is no doubt that some personal exhaustion played a role in my decision to leave, the main catalyst was the professional wall that I had reached as a software engineer. The system I had built and maintained for the past months was stable. We were just reaching the final stages of improvements that would fix the last remaining niggles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Again, World!</title>
      <link>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 18:13:51 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.race-conditions.net/posts/new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been blogging about the technology industry, software engineering and machine learning for a while over at winterflower.github.io. Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve also accumulated lots of notes about various technical and tech career related topics that I would like to share and so I&amp;rsquo;m starting up a new blog, here at race-conditions.
As some of you may know, I left my permanent software engineer position last July to focus on bootstrapping an open source technology company here in London.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>